ALL CHARACTERS, LOCATIONS,
ORGANIZATIONS, RELIGIONS,
EVENTS, AND OCCUPATIONS
IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS
The building representative
took Mr. Kim out,
and they both seemed weird…
Hi.
Mr. Kim.
Hey.
Are you thirsty too?
Don't you dare mess with her.
If you have anything to say, talk to me.
You too, Mr. Kim.
Sae-bom, we should look for the infected.
They might not know
if they've been infected or not.
Detective, stand up straight.
You're restoring order.
This house still has lots of food
and drinking water left.
We'll be staying home,
so please stop this and leave.
Right now.
I'm running out of patience.
Look at her, glaring at me.
Come on. Aim your gun at her!
That guy really is nuts.
Look here.
Are you looking for something?
What should I get you?
I was just…
It doesn't seem like a newlyweds' home.
It does without you here.
By the way, we shouldn't let
the kid stay here, should we?
What if she gets bitten by you two?
Then where should she go to?
To your house?
That's an option.
I'm good at babysitting.
I can tutor her too.
You're here to find the drugs, right?
The drug that gives you Mad Human Disease.
Give me that, hide in here and keep quiet.
Then I'll let you live here.
What are you going to do with it?
Your previous plan
to infect everyone failed.
I thought about it,
and my wife came back to life
because she took that drug,
even though her head was crushed.
When I'm in danger,
I'll take that drug too.
Then there's no possibility of dying
from excessive bleeding
after getting bitten by those monsters.
I can get the disease without any pain.
- Aren't you scared of the disease?
- What's so bad about it?
I won't fear anything if I get it.
Mister, this isn't some narcotic.
What were you doing there?
Weren't you on the third floor?
I got permission from the detective
at Unit 501 and moved there.
Is something the matter?
We heard the people
from that house got the disease.
Did they not try to bite you, like this?
No, they didn't.
Honey, did they really get the disease?
You'll be responsible for everything
that happens afterward.
Now, all of you who are here,
let's gather and talk.
We need to discuss
what to do with Unit 501.
Everyone!
Go have a meeting
at the building representative's house.
It's totally empty. There's nothing there!
It'll still have a lot of space
even if everyone here
all goes in there, right?
Detective!
Sae-bom, what's wrong with you?
Sae-bom, take a deep breath and relax.
Goodbye.
Let's go inside.
Sae-bom.
Are you okay?
Aren't you thirsty?
I'm really disappointed in you.
The building representative's house
sounds like a good spot.
And we'll get to see the royal floor too.
Yes, our unit was too shabby
to have valuable guests like you people.
We're not done cleaning the house yet.
That doesn't matter.
The building representative's house
sounds nice.
Let's go, then.
- Let's go.
Come, let's go.
Are you okay?
Do you think I'd wish
for Sae-bom to get the disease?
I was just worried. You saw it too.
That scar on her hand…
That really is nothing, Jung-kook.
It's just a wound.
You're worrying about nothing.
Yi-hyun, you go inside first.
I'll make sure to guard this place.
When nothing happens
even after a few days,
I'm sure they won't be worried anymore.
Jung-kook, be careful.
You must never trust those people.
This house is really far off.
It really is.
I know, right?
The royal floor has its weaknesses too.
I sacrificed myself
and went down all the time.
Next time, let's just talk down there.
There's nothing here.
Do you really live here?
By the way, this could get you charged
a lot for cleaning.
Why does a pastor drink so much?
More than that,
what should we do with the infected?
You all saw Ms. Yoon's reaction, right?
She can break in anytime at this rate.
Remember what the lawyer said?
Emergency evacuation.
But I don't see him today.
I'll tell you.
It's hard to apply that article
because it's their house,
and the disease did not occur yet.
Right, they didn't cause
any harm or anything.
I have evidence that the female
cop on the fifth floor is infected.
It may be better
to just kick her out of there.
Human beings tend to be strangely brave
when they have nothing
or nobody to back them up.
The disease occurs when they drink water.
The water in that house…
Wouldn't it be more dangerous
if it's there?
Right.
They have a lot of water,
but we can't just throw it away.
The lockdown is getting longer
and everyone must be having difficulties.
So let's share them equally
among all the residents.
Seriously…
They're all so mean.
But they're not bad people.
It's just because they're scared.
- Is the man at Unit 601 scared too?
- Except for him.
Don't go near him, and don't talk to him.
Treat him like he doesn't exist.
- Don't even look at him.
- Right.
But how can Mr. Kim do that to us?
We've known each other
for more than ten years.
I'm not trying to defend him,
but he has been away from home
for a long time now.
He must be worried and
miss his wife very much.
You know I score people, right?
Points for doing good things,
and deductions for doing bad things.
Mr. Kim has reached minus now.
Give some of my points to him.
I'm sure I have a lot of points.
I'm above zero, right?
The detective went up.
Went up to where?
People are upstairs,
planning to kick you two out.
I told him that, and he went up.
Kick us out to where?
Outside. They're also planning
to take your water and food.
Stay here with Seo-yoon.
Sae-bom!
Yoon Sae-bom! Stay calm!
Are you worried?
Not about Sae-bom…
but about the others.
She's a public official,
so if she bites someone,
she'll lose her house.
You all know it, don't you?
Sae-bom was so happy to live
in an apartment!
You live in the same apartment.
Why are you doing this?
Sae-bom, why are you here?
I'll explain everything,
so you go home first.
Detective, what are you doing?
She's holding a knife!
What were you all talking about?
What? Are you going to shoot?
And kill us all?
Hey, Sae-bom. Calm down.
It's okay, just let her be!
She doesn't even have the guts to shoot!
Go ahead and shoot!
Police officers always
leave the first round empty.
Now what are you going to do?
Are you going to scare us
and live here, infected?
I just came here because I got angry.
Since we're all here anyway,
should we look for the infected?
Is there a way?
I'm sure you all know
that the infected feel thirsty.
So what would happen
if they see human blood
after holding it in
and hiding their thirst?
Where's the blood?
Here.
Darn it.
It's okay.
She quieted down a moment ago.
What should we do now?
We must wait for now,
until she's able to communicate.
Since Mr. Kim is here,
let's go up and get you treated.
The smell of blood will only
make it harder for Bo-ram.
You stay here.
We have to find out
if she got bitten or took drugs.
Okay, I'll ask her later.
Hey.
Let's hurry. It'll be serious
if you get a bacterial infection.
Calm down, okay?
I have a strong immune system.
Ms. Lee is moving.
I'll go up alone,
so you go ahead in there.
I know how to do simple first aid.
I just need to stop the bleeding.
Put ointment on,
and cover it with a new towel.
Put your hand up high,
and lie down.
Give me some water too, please.
That scared the crap out of me.
This isn't yours!
All of you should go now.
This is not the right time
for a discussion.
Honey, let's go.
You're all still here.
What is it now?
You can't just go.
Sae-bom went through all that trouble.
Gosh.
We must find everyone infected
until the end.
Mr. Oh, we don't know
if you're infected, either.
Don't you think so?
You too, building representative.
I'm going in.
You should get out now.
I might change again soon.
Don't worry. You came back to normal,
so it won't happen again for a while.
I'm here to talk
about something important.
We must find out where you got infected.
We need to be prepared.
Did you…
get drugs from the gym, by any chance?
I got infected at the supermarket.
I think I got my leg scratched
when I hid from the infected.
I was scared that they wouldn't
let me into the apartment if I told them.
No one's going to come here,
so get some rest.
Thank you.
If it wasn't for you,
I would have bitten someone.
You don't know that.
Perhaps you would've been able
to hold it in, without biting anyone.
Did you throw away a bloody towel
by the emergency stairs?
In a trash bag?
No, that wasn't me.
Why? Is something out there?
I hear something from outside.
From the golf course.
Isn't Mr. Na there?
You…
just need to say the woman
on the fifth floor seems infected.
What?
I think I heard something from over there.
No one would come down
when there's an infected here.
Do you play golf?
Just screen golf, occasionally.
Then you can practice comfortably here.
You get out as a single player.
When the cure is out,
you should get a shot and go home safely.
Your family won't like it if they find out
that you got Mad Human Disease.
Is it because of the woman
on the fifth floor?
Because she's in the SOU?
I was in the military too. The KATUSA.
And I was in
the National Guard in Kentucky.
I could tell straight away. She's nothing.
Are you sure?
Are you sure you were in the army?
I was a military chaplain.
You should go home now.
I'm sure your wife is quite shocked.
Leave the golf club here.
When you go downstairs,
explain the situation to others,
and be careful of each other.
- And always meet in groups.
- Okay.
You've done so much.
You should be careful
not to get infected too.
Don't worry. I'm always careful.
Change your pants when you get home.
I think they're wet.
Please go so I can be alone.
You should stay home for a while too.
It might have an incubation period.
Honey.
What's going on?
- What are you doing?
- I saw blood.
The couple from the fifth floor
did something crazy again.
I need to gather the residents again.
This time, we will get rid
of the infected inside for good.
Where have you been?
You said you'd stay home.
I did. With my hand up, and lying in bed.
But I got a better idea on my way up.
Let's see how much better that idea was.
Listen, okay?
Since I bled anyway,
I thought it'd be better
to find more infected people…
So did you find them? The infected?
No.
I mean, that's a good thing…
But this is not good.
You can put ointment on it.
It will heal soon.
Let's go inside.
What are you doing there?
I was too ashamed to see you guys.
I was gullible,
so I just caused trouble for you…
I'll just stay on the second floor
or in the gym.
I can't face Seo-yoon, either.
Forget it. Hurry up and come inside.
We have to treat Yi-hyun's wound.
Mr. Kim.
Cheer up.
From now on,
tell us if you have any concerns.
Don't betray us.
That was…
That was my first time betraying anyone.
Jeez.
- Let's go inside.
- Right.
Thanks.
Hey.
I promise to live a good life.
Come on, let's go inside.
Mister, are you badly hurt?
No, it's just a scratch.
Not by the infected. By a knife.
- Hey…
- I just cut myself.
Seo-yoon, he needs to be treated,
so let's wait outside.
- I harmed myself…
- Hey.
Sit here.
How could you suddenly cause such trouble
when you seemed totally fine?
What could I have done?
Just watch you do it yourself
and compliment you
for making a nice, clean cut?
You and I are not the same.
I would've made a small cut,
for just a few drops.
You only needed to scare them,
not cover the place with your blood.
It's because I'm passionate.
I only bled a bit.
My blood vessels are all fine, look.
Do I look that dumb?
See? It's fine.
It's not?
Will my hand be damaged forever?
It won't need stitches.
Okay.
Don't do this next time.
I feel sick seeing you hurt.
My stomach doesn't feel good.
I don't think I can eat dinner.
Same for me.
All those people were staring at you
and you held up a knife,
trying to cut yourself.
- So how could I just stand there?
- Then what about me?
It's okay for me to do this,
but you shouldn't do it.
- Why?
- Just don't do it when I say so.
Don't overreact.
She's infected. Why is she still there?
Be quiet.
You said that she is infected.
Is she really tied up?
Can you move aside?
I'll take her, so you wrap up
the situation here.
Damn it.
Where do you want to go?
There's space in the golf course.
I feel stuffy.
I'd like to go to an open place.
Okay.
Everyone who can come is all here.
The 15th floor guy never joins us,
and the family on the third floor
said they'll just stay home.
The pastor isn't here.
He said he's not feeling well.
- Make sure to check if he's infected too.
- What did you say?
Please calm down.
The cleaning lady isn't here, either.
By any chance…
Is she at your house?
No, she isn't at our house.
Didn't she go to the basement?
There's an employee lounge there.
Let's not drag this and find the infected.
You said they go insane
when they see blood.
I am not infected. I'm serious.
Detective, please speed it up…
- Get me a cup.
- Okay.
Well then…
Mr. Lawyer, you can do this yourself.
We have a knife too.
Fill half the cup,
like during a urine test.
Come on, that's what
a police officer should do.
You're already wounded too.
Yes, he's right.
You want me to open my wound again?
The police are not blood donors.
Anyone who wants to do it can do it.
No one?
Would this be enough?
Stop the bleeding.
Do you all feel relieved now?
Here.
If there's anyone infected here…
there may be a sign, don't you think?
Seriously…
Come here.
Be careful.
Look at it straight.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
So, none of us here are infected, right?
Right.
Now then, let's discuss food.
I heard you people
are trying to make a killing.
You were demanding ridiculous
amounts of money.
What do you mean, ridiculous?
Demand and supply. Capitalism.
You live in such fancy apartments,
and you can't even pay that much?
You're being rude.
Why are you talking down to us?
I didn't talk rudely!
You just talked rudely, again!
And what do you know about capitalism?
WONJUNG DORMITORY
A new variant has been confirmed
among severe patients.
How is it different?
It can control the timing
of the occurrence.
It suppresses the thirst most of the time,
and it occurs only when it's convinced
that it won't get caught.
This disease is as cunning as humans.
The authorities want follow-up measures,
but it's difficult to secure those
infected with the variant.
How's his current condition?
We injected a tranquilizer cocktail.
It would keep him in
a normal state for ten minutes,
but he has a high chance of
being unable to recover ever again.
Ten minutes would be enough.
How have you been?
I'm a bit late. I had a lot
of work to do because of you.
The funeral went well.
Some cried when they heard
you volunteered for the clinical test.
When everything's over, you might
receive a Medal of National Merit.
Your children were crying a lot.
You didn't tell them the account number
for your slush fund, did you?
Do you think it'll end like this?
Of course, it won't.
We still have a lot of tests to conduct.
The authorities…
are all getting you to make
the dirty decisions, aren't they?
Do you think you'll become someone big
if you hold out until the cure is out?
That won't happen.
Once the hunt is over,
the hounds become useless.
Your wife, your kid…
They will all become like me.
You have five minutes left
to speak with sanity.
The hound…
If I secure the cure…
who do you think
would be treated as the hound?
What about Ms. Yoon's blood analysis?
The result will be out tomorrow
at the earliest.
You need severe patients with the variant?
Yes.
They hide their thirst well,
and we can't tell just by looking.
And we can't neglect
those who are already infected
until they get the variant.
Seyang Forest.
A lot of severe patients are there.
It's been ten days since the lockdown.
That means there might have been
enough mutations.
Is that why you insisted on the lockdown?
To track down the mutation of the virus?
We have to find out
how the virus mutates in a natural state.
So it's like a petri dish
containing a collection of germs.
And you must've thought
that an antibody may have formed,
if you were lucky.
Make a small opening,
just enough for one person to squeeze out.
Then the infected
will come out on their own,
so catch and study them.
Did you tell your husband
before you came here?
I have a favor to ask.
Do you have items needed
for outdoor survival?
And can you please give me
some water and food too?
It's not for me.
There's someone on the rooftop.
Stay here for a while.
I'll keep all the doors blocked.
Thank you so much.
I brought some water and food.
I'll go get some more from my house.
Please don't bring any water.
The more I drink it, the thirstier I get.
It's better to just wet my lips a bit.
The cooler…
You didn't drink water then, right?
I didn't.
Who else didn't drink water there?
I only put a small amount of water in it.
Drink the water in small amounts,
and tell me if you feel thirsty.
I'll untie you while you eat…
Don't come near me.
When someone gets closer,
my thirst gets worse.
I'm okay. I'll just eat like this.
Were you okay yesterday?
I heard the pastor on
the 12th floor came here.
Didn't you have a long talk with him?
But…
I didn't want to attack him.
Looks like the disease
is choosy about people.
Even mosquitoes bite
only one person out of many people.
Jung-kook, you said that the infected
did not attack the pastor?
He's very religious.
He has spiritual powers.
Our Father in heaven,
hallowed be your name,
your kingdom come,
your will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us today our daily bread,
daily bread, daily…
You still haven't cleaned the blood?
Did you find any other infected?
Not yet.
I need to go to the 3rd floor
and the 15th floor too.
It'll be nice to say
that I protected the apartment,
don't you think?
It's blood. We need something
to catch the infected with.
It's from that guy on the second floor
who keeps his face covered,
but he's weird too.
Bite me if you want to.
What?
I said, did I lose my hair?
A little bit.
What?
Really?
Darn it!
Where am I missing my hair the most?
No, I think you're fine.
Hey.
How's Bo-ram?
She's fine.
More than that, the water from the cooler…
Yes?
The pastor didn't drink it.
I thought of that too.
The infected didn't bite the pastor.
Right? It's a cult.
- Isn't it weird?
- Let's go and check.
The purpose of the virus
is to spread the disease.
So they stop drinking blood
when the victim is infected.
Would the infected bite each other
when they're together?
- They wouldn't.
- Right?
It makes sense to not feel
the thirst for each other.
Then the pastor is also…
We have to go check.
This is just a misunderstanding.
Yeon-ok, let's…
Let's talk face to face, okay?
Why would I do that, you jerk?
When did you get infected?
Seung-beom gave me drugs.
There must have been something in them.
Then you should've told me!
If I told you,
you wouldn't have forgiven me!
I tried to hold it in too.
I tried drinking my own blood,
but it's no use.
The thirst only gets worse.
This is hard for me too!
Should I just go down to the gym?
Woo-chang, it's been so hard for us.
If they find out about your disease,
I won't be able to become
the resident representative.
We can't just give up like this!
Then what should we do?
If you stay in your room,
I will give you food.
Okay?
Let's just tell them that you're sick.
If you wait for a few days,
the soldiers will come.
Just hang in there. Can you do that?
Honey.
Woo-chang?
Woo-chang!
Anybody home?
Should we break the door?
Hey, calm down.
You should be the one calming me down.
Sometimes we need to switch our roles.
Building representative!
Is the pastor home?
No.
He went outside.
Are you sure he's not home?
Pastor, I'd like to pray.
What are you doing here?
We had a few more things to discuss.
And the weather is hot…
The pastor…
Hey!
Doesn't this look more delicious?
Looks like it needs ointment again.
Let's go.
Once they smell blood,
their symptoms get worse.
Go in there when he calms down.
Did your thoughts
on the infected change now?
You killed him.
You did…
Have you been here this whole time?
It seemed like the infected were outside.
Did you take care of it?
You were scared, weren't you?
I should've protected you…
I know you're going to do that
from now on. I trust you.
Oh Joo-hyung was with the pastor.
He might've been infected.
Then what should I do?
I can't stay at your house, either.
I'll talk to my wife about it--
No.
She'll find out about our relationship.
But still…
I told you.
Oh Joo-hyung's bankruptcy is fake.
He invested everything in cryptocurrency.
Once we know the passcode to
his account, it'll all be ours.
Okay?
Where have you been?
Did you hear the man
on the 12th floor died?
Yes, I was pretty shocked,
so I went to the rooftop to get some air.
The rooftop? But Ms. Lee is there.
She is, I just sat in front of the door.
I was so shocked, you know.
The man's eyes turned all white, and…
You should've seen it.
By the way, let's say that you have
a very important passcode.
Something very long and complex,
something no one should find out.
Where would you hide it?
I should memorize it.
Or write it somewhere
the others don't know about,
so only I'd know.
Are you thirsty?
You're not feeling sick, are you?
You washed your hair
when we have no water?
I couldn't help it.
It was itchy and greasy.
And don't worry.
We'll have a source of water soon.
Don't ever do this again.
We don't even have antibiotics.
I'm a human vitamin
and a human antibiotic.
I'm totally fine.
The pastor from the 12th floor…
It wasn't our fault.
I know.
I still feel bad.
He should've told us that he was sick.
It's hard to confess
to being infected by the disease.
And they'd be scared
about wanting to bite the others.
And they might think they could
get the cure if they just hold out.
And it would also hurt…
to think someone they care about
might get scared of them.
Why? Do I have a fever?
I have a fever.
You have fever medicine, right?
I'll take that just in case,
and let's rest tomorrow.
And not do anything.
Good night.
Am I okay?
Go to sleep.
Honey.
We had no idea.
How could they have done this?
I heard the pastor
on the 12th floor was infected.
He passed away.
Please wish for him to rest in peace.
Unbelievable.
That couple tricked all of us.
I think you two should restore
order around here.
Did you come here to say that?
That, and we're here for water too.
You know everyone's short on water, right?
We saw that you had a lot
of water in your house.
You want some of our water?
- Yes.
- You and the 15th floor.
The others went to the 15th floor.
I went to the rooftop,
and the supermarket lady said
she's not going to drink water,
and she gave us this.
You didn't mess with Ms. Lee, did you?
Goodness, why would we mess with her?
The infected are scary, you know.
This is the water
from the 15th floor, right?
That guy has a lot of water
at home, right?
He does.
Right, we should go there first.
We should've gone there first.
When is it going to rain?
What?
I feel nothing.
By the way…
should we give out our water too?
We're fine, but Seo-yoon…
More than that, the 15th floor…
People went to the 15th floor.
Excuse me, please open the door. We…
What is it?
You have a lot of water, right?
Everyone's having a hard time.
Share some with us.
The lockdown will be over
in a few days, anyway.
What if it doesn't?
I'll pay you, so share some.
These cleaners sell water
for 200,000 won per 500ml.
That's even more expensive than oil.
If you think it's unfair, you do it too.
Excuse me, we'll talk to him.
- You should go.
- But…
- Doing this won't solve anything.
- The residents should get along.
- You might need legal consulting someday!
- Hi.
You know the doctor
has a dirty temper, right?
- He may set this place on fire.
- Don't say that!
- I get it, so…
- Let's talk for a minute.
Go ahead.
I'm sorry.
I asked you for all sorts of things…
With what's going on,
how about sharing some water
if you have a lot left?
You'd only have to share
a little bit of it.
You don't have to do it,
but please think about it.
If things really get hard,
we'll go outside and get some.
You don't need to go outside.
Building 103 has EPS…
Emergency Power Supply,
in the electrical room
under the senior citizens' center.
It's made to turn on
emergency lights for elevators.
If you turn on the general power,
the electricity and water
will be turned on.
But it's turned on with a diesel
generator, so it will be quite noisy.
So the infected will all come
when they hear it.
We'll discuss what to do.
Tomorrow…
morning…
I will sort out what
I can give out tomorrow morning.
You're going to share with everyone?
- Sir, bless you.
- Thank you.
Bless you.
- Will he give us water?
- What about anything else?
It seems like he has a lot of food.
It's only right to share the water!
Please tell him to share it with us.
Calm down, please.
We will share what we have first.
He said he'll think about it
until tomorrow, so don't bother him.
Let's go.
He has a lot of water, right?
- He might change his mind…
- Let's go!
- Come on.
- He could change his mind.
Come on, let's go downstairs.
Hasn't Han Tae-seok contacted us yet?
No. It looks like he'll contact us
when he wants to.
- What are you looking for?
- You see…
I got this when I was training
for the FBI SWAT team.
And it's a large size.
What about it?
I want to say thank you
to the man on the 15th floor.
He's a bit cranky, but he's generous.
I have a T-shirt
from the Italian Championships.
- Shall we take that too?
- No, keep that one.
Honey.
Yes, Young-in, it's me.
Everything seems like a dream.
I feel like I'd be home
when I wake up, but…
What about our baby?
She's fine.
Honey.
Can't you take our baby out first?
There's a high chance of her
being born infected
because she shares your blood.
Honey.
Yes?
Never give up…
on our baby, okay?
Okay.
We can't postpone the childbirth anymore.
You will have to make a decision.
If miscarriage were possible,
it would've happened already.
If anything happens to the baby,
it may worsen her state of infection.
You still have to choose.
You have to choose whom
you're going to save
if you can save only one.
I only have one choice.
Ms. Yoon's blood test result is out.
She has the antibody.
I'll be back.
Want me to go with you?
No, he seems to get sensitive
whenever he sees you.
That's how shy people are.
I'll be back soon.
Be careful.
Mr. Jung.
I'm listening.
What did he mean by a wrongdoing
that can't be undone?
We got the background check results
for those in the apartment,
and something's weird.
Do you think Kim Se-hoon really did this?
Someone died.
That's not important right now.
The food is gone!
Are you in danger?
Get the infiltration team ready.
Please help us so Sae-bom can live safely.
This will be my last favor.
Yi-hyun!
Subtitle translation by: Hae-lim Lee